Guide to the Susan M. Chambré Research Files on Volunteer AIDS Organizations
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Susan M. Chambré research files on volunteer AIDS organizations
1981-2015
MS 2054
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.25
(13 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material collected by Susan M. Chambré for her research on AIDS organizations and advocacy. This research was used for a series of articles in professional journals as well as the book Fighting for Our Lives: New York's AIDS Community and the Politics of Disease (Rutgers University Press, 2006). The material includes annual reports, unpublished reports, newsletters, news clippings, journal articles, pamphlets, board minutes and other material from nearly 100 AIDS-related organizations. Materials date from 1981 to 2015.
Chambré, Susan Maizel
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material collected by Susan M. Chambré for her research on AIDS organizations and advocacy. This research was used for a series of articles in professional journals as well as the book Fighting for Our Lives: New York's AIDS Community and the Politics of Disease (Rutgers University Press, 2006). The material includes annual reports, unpublished reports, newsletters, news clippings, journal articles, pamphlets, board minutes and other material from nearly 100 AIDS-related organizations. Materials date from 1981 to 2015.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series: I. Topical files, 1984-2013. II. AIDS organization files, 1981-2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Susan Maizel Chambré, 2016.
Biographical / Historical
Susan M. Chambré is a sociologist and academic whose scholarly work focuses on civic engagement, nonprofit organizations and public policy. She received her B.A. in Sociology from Queens College, City University of New York and her A.M. and Ph.D from the University of Pennsylvania. She was a research scientist at the New York City Human Resources Administration. She later became a professor and taught at the State University of New York at Stony Brook, Yeshiva University, and Baruch College, City University of New York, where she retired from in 2016. She has published several books, including Patients, Consumers and Civil Society (2008), Fighting for Our Lives: New York's AIDS Community and the Politics of Disease (2006), and Good Deeds in Old Age: Volunteering by the New Leisure Class (1987). She has also published several articles in journals such as Nonprofit and Voluntary Sector Quarterly and Nonprofit Management and Leadership.
Separated Materials
Copies of the newsletter Newsline, published by the People With AIDS Coalition (PWAC) and dating from 1986 to 1999, were separated from the collection and added to the General Collection at Sterling Memorial Library.
AIDS activists -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Services for -- New York (State) -- New York; Community health services; LGBTQ resource; Chambré, Susan Maizel
- Topical files, 1984-2013; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series comprises research materials related to New York City AIDS organizations, often from a local govenrment perspective. Materials include reports on addressing the AIDS crisis in New York City and New York State, information on funding from both government and private sources, and research on policy.
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Funding
    - Concerned funders, 1992-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Funding guides, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fundraising, 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hoffman LaRoche, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - MetLife, Circa 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mutual of New York Foundation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - New York, New York, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Ryan White CARE Act, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Policy
    - Medicaid, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - New York, New York, 1983-2013 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - New York State, 1984-2007 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Reports
    - Committee for AIDS Funding, Circa 1992-circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Management of AIDS services, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - New York AIDS Coalition, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - New York City AIDS Fund, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - New York City Interagency Task Force on AIDS, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Risk group, women, 1989-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- AIDS organization files, 1981-2015; Series II
  This series comprises materials collected from different AIDS advocacy organizations based in New York City. These materials can include pamphlets, fliers, newsletters, printouts from organization websites, memoranda, and correspondence. There are also newspaper and magazine articles written about the organizations. The organization that is the most heavily documented is the People With AIDS Coalition; other prominent organizations include Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC) and the Association for Drug Abuse and Treatment (ADAPT). There are also some general materials, including several directories of AIDS-related organizations.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by organization.
  - General
    - Directories, 1986-2003 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Religious organizations, 1983-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - AIDS and Adolescents Network, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - AIDS Center of Queens County, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - AIDS Community Research Initiative of America (ACRIA), 1989-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - AIDS Counseling and Education (ACE Out), 1989-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - AIDS Family Service, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - AIDS in Prison Project, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - AIDS Interfaith New York, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - AIDS Service Center of Lower Manhattan, 1992-2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - AIDS Theater Project, 1989-2002 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - AIDS Treatment Data Network, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - AIDS Wasting Foundation, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - AIDSfilms, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Action Against AIDS, 1995-2002 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ads Against AIDS, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Aid for AIDS, 2000-2004 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - American Foundation for AIDS Research (AMFAR), 1983-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - American Run for the End of AIDS, 1985-2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Asian and Pacific Islander Coalition on HIV/AIDS (APICHA)
    - General, 1989-2014 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters, 1995-2015 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Association for Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment (ADAPT)
    - General, 1985-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Financial records, 1986-1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bailey House
    - General, 1985-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Financial records, 1988-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - History, 1987-2004 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Balm in Gilead, 1989-2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Black and Latino AIDS Coalition, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Body Positive
    - General, 1990-2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Financial records, 1988-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Broadway Cares, 1993-2006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bronx AIDS Service, 1986-2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bronx AIDS Volunteer Organization (Project BRAVO), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn AIDS Task Force, 1986-1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cable Positive, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Children's Hope Fund, 1996-2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Citizens United for Research and Education (CURE), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Concerned Parents for AIDS Research, 1998-2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Design Industries Foundation Fighting Aids (DIFFA), 1984-2002 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Determined Involved Supermodels Helping to End Suffering (DISHES) Project, Incorporated, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Estate Project, 1992-2002 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family Center, 1997-2006 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Foundation for Research on Sexually Transmitted Diseases, Incorporated (FROST'D), 1990-2003 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Friends House, 1999-2006 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Friends in Need, 1993-2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Funders Concerned about AIDS, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gay Men's Health Crisis Incorporated (GMHC)
    - General, 1982-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12-13, Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Angels on Ice, 1994-10-24 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1986-2002 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
    - Diversity, 1989-1999 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Volunteer, 1987-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7-8, Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Gay Men of African Descent, 1996-2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - God's Love We Deliver
    - General, 1986-2010 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - Clients, meals, 1993-2003 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Finances, 1988-1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - History, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Nutrition, 1989-1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Haitian Coalition on AIDS, Circa 1982-circa 2015 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Harlem United/Upper Room AIDS Ministry
    - General, 1991-2008 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
    - History, 1991-2013 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Health Education AIDS Liaison (HEAL), 1986-2006 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Health Force, 1994-2006 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hearts and Voices, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hell's Kitchen AIDS Project, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - HighBridge, 1989-2005 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hispanic AIDS Forum, 1985-2004 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Housing Works, 1993-2004 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - HIV Arts Network, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - HIV Law Project, 1995-2006 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Illusion Productions, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Incarnation Children's Center, 1997-2002 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Iris House, 1990-2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Board of Family and Children's Services, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - La Familia Unida, Circa 1981-circa 2015 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Latino Commission on AIDS, 1989-2000 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Center, 1983-1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lifebeat, 1992-2006 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - LifeForce, 1993-2006 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Living with AIDS Fund, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Love Heals, 1990-2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lower East Side Harm Reduction Center, 1997-2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Manhattan Center for Living, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Manhattan Plaza, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Middle East Natives, Testing, Orientation, and Referral Services (MENTORS) New York, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Minority Task Force on AIDS, 1992-2007 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Miracle House, 1992-2014 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Momentum
    - General, 1986-2014 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - History, 1986-2002 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Mother's Love, 1988-1998 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Mothers of Children with AIDS (MOCA), 1998 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Mother's March Against AIDS, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Mother's Voices, 1992-2006 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Multitasking (MTS), 1988-2006 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Names Project, 1987-2002 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - National AIDS Memorial, 1986-2002 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - National AIDS Treatment Advocacy Project (NATAP), 2001-2008 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - National Black Leadership Commission on AIDS, 1985-2006 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - New York AIDS Coalition, 1988-2005 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - New York AIDS Network, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - New York City Department of Health, Circa 2002-Circa 2015 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - New York Harm Reduction Educators, 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Northern Lights, 1988-1998 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Parent AIDS Initiative, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - People with AIDS Coalition, 1987-2002 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - People with AIDS (PWA) Health Group, 1987-1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - People with AIDS (PWA) Theater Workshop, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Pet Owners with AIDS Resource Service (POWARS), 1989-1997 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Photographers and Friends United Against AIDS, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pineapple Alliance, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Positive Action and Anonymous, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Positive Health Project, 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Queens AIDS Pastoral Care, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Safer Sex Committee, 1984-1994 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Red Hot, 1990-1998 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Sex Panic, 1997-1999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Sisterhood Mobilized, 2001-2006 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Stamp Out AIDS, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Stand Up Harlem, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Staten Island AIDS Task Force, 1988-2002 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Saint Ann's Corner of Harm Reduction, 1998-2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tamarand Foundation, Incorporated, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Outreach Using Communal Healing (TOUCH), Circa 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Tzvi Aryeh AIDS Foundation, 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Upper Manhattan Task Force, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Village Center for Care AIDS Program/Rivington House, 1988-2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Visual AIDS, 1989-2006 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Women's HIV Collaborative, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Youth Organizers United, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Women and AIDS Resource Network (WARN), 1987-2007 (Box 13, Folder 15)